GREGORY VANDER SCHUEREN RESUME

Software Engineer

Status: R&D Engineer, Tessares **Field:** Software Engineering

Interests & skills: Open-source software, GNU/Linux, Kubernetes, Cloud-native computing, DevOps practices, CI/CD tooling, Computer networking, Web development, Entrepreneurship, Network function virtualization, eBPF, XDP, Golang, C, Bash, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, etc.

29 yrs old, Brussels, Belgium gregory.vanderschueren@gmail.com +32 495 51 77 21 Speaks English & French

Summary

Passionate software engineer (5 years experience). Graduated both in Computer Science and Business Administration. Experienced in designing, developing, and adapting to complex computer systems. Always willing to learn and looking for new technical challenges. Strong believer in DevOps and CI/CD tooling and best-practices. Strong background in business and entrepreneurship with excellent communication skills. Optimist and enthusiastic by nature.

Experience

HAG-VNF Engineer - Tessares

2019 - present

- · Architecture, prototyping and implementation of Tessares HAG as a VNF (Virtual Network Function) using Cloud Native principles and technologies (Kubernetes, OpenStack, Heat, Prometheus, Fluentd, Elasticsearch, Jaeger, custom Kubernetes operators, gRPC, etc).
- · Wrote Tessares's XDP-based (eBPF) layer 4 load-balancer powering our HAG-VNF.
- · Contributing to Tessares standardization efforts to push the "O-RTT TCP Convert" protocol at the IETF. Co-authored the first open-source implementation and added support into Tessares' closed source HAG.

R&D Engineer - Tessares

2017 - 2019

- · Development and maintenance of Tessares's Hybrid Access Gateyway (HAG), a performance critical layer 4 proxy that provides Hybrid Internet access to hundreds of thousands of households.
- · Troubleshooting and bug-fixing Tessares's custom Linux kernel, a patched version of the open-source Linux Multipath TCP Kernel implementation.
- \cdot Part-time research work in collaboration with Olivier Bonaventure's research team at the IP Networking Lab of the Louvain School of Engineering.

Full-stack Engineer & Co-Founder - Famest

2012 - 2014

- · Photo sharing social network for fashionistas. 230.000€ in funding.
- \cdot Ruby on Rails, iOS, web front-end, hosted on AWS. Application with 100K+ users and 1M+ photos.

Education

Computer Science, Master Degree - École polytechnique de Louvain

2015 - 2017

- \cdot Graduated top 1 of my promotion (Plus Grande Distinction Summa Cum Laude).
- · Specialization in Security and Networking. Master Thesis: TCPSnitch, dissecting the socket API usage.

Computer Science, Bachelor Degree - École polytechnique de Louvain

2014 - 2015

· Completed this 3-years program at an accelerated pace in 1 year (Grande Distinction - Magna Cum Laude).

Management, Master Degree - Louvain School of Management

2011 - 2013

- · Graduated top 1 of my promotion for the second year of master (18.52/20 GPA), while I co-founded Famest.
- · Cross-disciplinary master program in entrepreneurship (CPME).
- · Exchange semester at the University of Texas at Austin. Perfect 4.0 GPA.

Economics & Management, Bachelor Degree - Université Catholique de Louvain

2008 - 2011

· Distinction - Cum Laude.